<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mortis Acadame</title><link>https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/</link><description>Confidence that encourages and sustains.</description><atom:link href="https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2017 &lt;a href="mailto:millejoh@mac.com"&gt;John M. Miller&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 21:56:55 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Introductions and Apologies</title><link>https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/posts/introductions-and-apologies/</link><dc:creator>John M. Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think the last time I genuinely tried to do one of these &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://radio.userland.com/"&gt;RadioUserland&lt;/a&gt; was the way to do it. Amazingly they still exist,
I think? Anyway the world has moved on and so should we, to some extent. This
new site takes advantage of the latest and greatest, and as such there is much
still to learn. Expect general instability until we eventually settle down on
some fixed sense of style and form. But ours is the way of the procrastination
and indecision, so in reality there may never be any sense of "done" around
here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ostensibly, this is where I will chronicle my (mis)adventures as an aging
engineer in this bold, new hipster world of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.apple.com"&gt;technology&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, I went there. But now I'm back. I don't hate
them, I truly don't; only that about 10 years ago I suddenly found myself not
cool enough and definitely not rich enough to continue the relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving on. We will try to keep our writing to things that interest us, like our
small labour of love, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://millejoh.github.io/emacs-ipython-notebook"&gt;Emacs Ipython Notebook&lt;/a&gt;, our interests in Machine
Learning and Data Science, and our occasional journeys as a traveling Chemical
Engineer. No promise, though, that things won't get a bit &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/pages/sadness"&gt;weird&lt;/a&gt; from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, welcome! Hope you enjoy your stay, no matter how short it may be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/posts/introductions-and-apologies/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 16:50:10 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>