<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mortis Acadame</title><link>https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/</link><description>Confidence that encourages and sustains.</description><atom:link href="https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:millejoh@mac.com"&gt;John M. Miller&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 04:27:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fiddle, fiddle, fiddle</title><link>https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/posts/fiddle-fiddle-fiddle/</link><dc:creator>John M. Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We really need some sort of unifying theme to these posts, but what would it be?
What hope is there in ever finding one? Thoughts become ever more scattered and
the things that compete for attention are legion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, as promised we continue to play around with themes and organization. What?
You thought this I had forgotten about this endeavor? Never! Anyway, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.edwardtufte.com/tufte/"&gt;Edward
Tufte&lt;/a&gt; is something of personal deity around these parts, so imagine the
excitement when our Investigations Department discovered the delightful &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://edwardtufte.github.io/tufte-css/"&gt;tufte
css&lt;/a&gt; for styling web pages. Tufte has inspired a generation of web designers
so it's nice to pay some homage from this site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things are far from perfect, though! While our Senior Editor finds the larger
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/edwardtufte/et-book"&gt;et-book&lt;/a&gt; font much easier on the eyes, he still is not sure about that very
wide left margin. Maybe someone else has done a better job elsewhere. Rumour is
that someone built a tufte theme for &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://jekyllrb.com/"&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. More work for the ID (as if they
didn't already have enough).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/posts/fiddle-fiddle-fiddle/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 04:03:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>On Wealth Bondage</title><link>https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/posts/on-wealth-bondage/</link><dc:creator>John M. Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am happy to say that &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/tarsius"&gt;Jonas Bernoulli's&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1681258897/its-magit-the-magical-git-client?ref=eei2el"&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; has been succesfully funded as of a few days ago. There still a
few days left, so feel free to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/71viq3/the_magit_kickstarter_has_reached_its_goal_heres/"&gt;contribute&lt;/a&gt;. More money is always good when it is
for a good cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My use case for git is honestly very simple as I do not contribute much to
projects other than ein and the development team for the same is simply me,
myself, and I. Even still, magit makes working with git easy and joyful and I am
glad this package exists. In case you are wondering, I did make a very modest
contribution to the campaign. If I had the means I would happily support more
Emacs developers, particularly the ones who have contributed work that make EIN
possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jonas did something particularly interesting and courageous in an effort to
promote his kickstarter: he added a modest, easily removed blurb on the magit
status screen. It seems some took &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/magit/magit/issues/3174#issuecomment-330091971"&gt;offence&lt;/a&gt; to the tactic. Unreasonably so, in
my opinion. It could not have been an easy decision for Jonas to take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think part of the problem is that we, and by we I mean U.S. citizens in
particular, have been conditioned to view the asking for help as an act of
despicable weakness- especially so when asking for money. There also seems to be
a bit of an attitude within some parts of the FOSS community that there really
are such things as free lunches. But that is a another topic worthy of its own
dedicated post, and I don't plan to get into it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also programmers can be sensitive to interruptions and distractions- I think
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://randsinrepose.com/archives/nadd/"&gt;Rands in Repose&lt;/a&gt; diagnosed this particular condition succintly long ago
- and advertisement is certainly up there on the list of non-value added
distractions. In all, though, I think Jonas handled his plea for assistance
elegantly and succinctly. I did not feel at all distracted or coereced into
contributing to his campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And contribute is the right word to use here, not give. Magit has helped me to
be succesful in my work, so it only seemed fair to contribute back to its
well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I take leave, I have had in the back of my mind some words I read long
ago by Phil Cubeta, he of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.gifthub.org/2010/05/to-whom-it-may-concern.html#tp"&gt;dungeon master&lt;/a&gt; to the stars. I can't find the
post, unfortunately, but it had to do with levels, or rather a hierarchy, of
giving and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.chabad.org/library/article_cdo/aid/45907/jewish/Eight-Levels-of-Charity.htm"&gt;charity&lt;/a&gt;. Luckily a google search quickly revealed the
aforementioned link, and the below summary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if all who struggle with the non-trivial issue of financially
supporting elisp package maintainers (and FOSS in general) wouldn't benefit at
least some from quiet consideration of Mainmonide's levels of charity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainmonide's 8 levels of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.chabad.org/library/article_cdo/aid/45907/jewish/Eight-Levels-of-Charity.htm"&gt;charity&lt;/a&gt; (follow that link, it is much better than
the summary below):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investing in a poor person in a manner that they can become self-sufficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving to the poor without knowledge of the recipient and without allowing
the recipient to know your identity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving to the poor with knowledge of the recipient but without allowing the
recipient to know your identity (anonymous giving).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving to the poor without knowledge of the recipient but allowing the
recipient to know your identity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving to the poor without or before being asked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving to the poor after being asked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving to the poor happily but inadequately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving to the poor unwillingly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/posts/on-wealth-bondage/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 14:54:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Introductions and Apologies</title><link>https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/posts/introductions-and-apologies/</link><dc:creator>John M. Miller</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think the last time I genuinely tried to do one of these &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://radio.userland.com/"&gt;RadioUserland&lt;/a&gt; was the way to do it. Amazingly they still exist,
I think? Anyway the world has moved on and so should we, to some extent. This
new site takes advantage of the latest and greatest, and as such there is much
still to learn. Expect general instability until we eventually settle down on
some fixed sense of style and form. But ours is the way of the procrastination
and indecision, so in reality there may never be any sense of "done" around
here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ostensibly, this is where I will chronicle my (mis)adventures as an aging
engineer in this bold, new hipster world of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.apple.com"&gt;technology&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, I went there. But now I'm back. I don't hate
them, I truly don't; only that about 10 years ago I suddenly found myself not
cool enough and definitely not rich enough to continue the relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving on. We will try to keep our writing to things that interest us, like our
small labour of love, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://millejoh.github.io/emacs-ipython-notebook"&gt;Emacs Ipython Notebook&lt;/a&gt;, our interests in Machine
Learning and Data Science, and our occasional journeys as a traveling Chemical
Engineer. No promise, though, that things won't get a bit &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/pages/sadness/"&gt;weird&lt;/a&gt; from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, welcome! Hope you enjoy your stay, no matter how short it may be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://millejoh.github.io/MortisAcadame/posts/introductions-and-apologies/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 16:50:10 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>